const QUESTIONS = [
    {
        "id": 1,
        "topic": "Sociology",
        "question": "What is sociology?",
        "answers": [
            "It is the study of society, human behavior, and social interactions.", 
            "It is the study of the moons, stars, and sun.", 
            "It is the study of the jungle and its fauna.", 
            "It is the study of the Earth's atmosphere and its chemical composition."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "topic": "Sociology",
        "question": "What does a sociologist study?",
        "answers": [
            "Sociologists study the Earth's atmosphere and its chemical composition.", 
            "Sociologists study the moon and its fauna.", 
            "Sociologists study social structures, institutions, and how people interact within communities.", 
            "Sociologists study the jungle and the lives of animals."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "topic": "Sociology",
        "question": "What is the role of culture in sociology?",
        "answers": [
            "The study of plant and animal cultivation.", 
            "Culture shapes behaviors, beliefs, and values within a society.", 
            "The chemical composition of substances.", 
            "Anatomy and functions of the human body."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "topic": "Sociology",
        "question": "Define social inequality.",
        "answers": [
            "The study of physical fitness and exercise.", 
            "A mathematical concept in calculus.", 
            "The process of converting solid to liquid.", 
            "Disparities in wealth, opportunities, and privileges among individuals or groups."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "topic": "Sociology",
        "question": `What is the significance of the "social contract" in sociology?`,
        "answers": [
            "A legal document between two individuals.", 
            "A business partnership agreement.", 
            "The implicit agreement within a society regarding mutual rights and responsibilities.", 
            "The rules of a chess game."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "topic": "Sociology",
        "question": `Explain the term "socialization."`,
        "answers": [
            "The study of planetary orbits.", 
            "The chemical reaction between acids and bases.", 
            "The process of converting raw materials into finished products.", 
            "The process by which individuals learn societal norms, values, and behaviors."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "topic": "Sociology",
        "question": `What is the role of a family in sociology?`,
        "answers": [
            "Families are studied as fundamental units influencing socialization and relationships.",
            "The study of geological formations.",
            "The role of vitamins in human health.",
            "The exploration of outer space."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "topic": "Sociology",
        "question": `Define "gender roles" in sociology.`,
        "answers": [
            "The roles of different types of musical instruments.",
            "The characteristics of chemical elements.",
            "The rules of a sports game.",
            "Societal expectations regarding behaviors considered appropriate for males and females."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "topic": "Sociology",
        "question": `What is the concept of "social mobility"?`,
        "answers": [
            "The process of generating electrical power.",
            "The study of ocean currents.",
            "The ability of individuals or groups to move within social hierarchies.",
            "The technique of mountain climbing."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "topic": "Sociology",
        "question": `How does sociology contribute to social change?`,
        "answers": [
            "Sociology helps identify atmospheric conditions.",
            "Sociology helps identify and address societal issues.",
            "The process of cellular respiration.",
            "The rules of a card game."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1
    }
]

export default QUESTIONS;